Guide to the Ford E. and Harriet R. Curtis Theatre Collection of Pittsburgh Performing Arts Photographs, 1914-present CTC.1966.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Theatres, 1914-1980; II.; 91 photographs
  - Nixon Theatre, 1950; 4 photographs
    The Nixon Theatre was opened in 1903 on the corner of Sixth Avenue and William Penn Place. The Nixon was the main theatre in Pittsburgh for Broadway touring productions. The final performance at the Nixon was in 1950. Photographs show the Nixon Theatre with marquees for Brigadoon, Oklahoma!, and the final performance at the Nixon, Diamond Lil, featuring Mae West.
  - Oakland Theatre, February 26, 1932; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of the Oakland Theatre at 205 Atwood Street looking east from the opposite side of the street. This photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1979-1980; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of the Pittsburgh Playhouse from the corner of Craft Avenue and Hamlet Street in Oakland. The Pittsburgh Playhouse began as a community theatre in 1934. The theatre was purchased by Point Park College in 1973 and has served as the venue for their performing arts productions through the present day.
  - Pittsburgh Theatre, 3 photographs
    Photographs are of the Pittsburgh Theatre on Fifth Avenue. The Pittsburgh Theatre was built in 1833 and later became known as the Old Drury Theater. The Old Drury was torn down in 1870.
  - Plaza Theater, August 1, 1937; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of the Plaza Theater on Liberty Avenue. Photograph is part of the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Roosevelt Theatre, September 23, 1932; 3 photographs
    Photographs are street views of the Roosevelt Theatre. Two photographs are on Center Avenue in front of the Irene Kaufman Settlement House. The third photograph is on the corner of Green and Linton Streets, looking South. The Roosevelt Theatre was a motion picture theatre located in the Hill District of Pittsburgh. These photographs are from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Schenley Theatre, July 17, 1936; 1 photograph
    Photograph is a view of Schenley Theatre from Forbes Street, looking East. Photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer Collection.
  - Sheridan Square Theatre, May 2, 1928; 1 photograph
    Photograph is taken looking East from a rooftop along Penn Avenue. The Sheridan Square Theatre was a Vaudeville Picture theatre. Photograph is from the Pittsburgh City Photographer's Collection. Collection also includes the photograph's negative.
  - Sherwood Forest Theatre, 1 photograph
    The Sherwood Forest Theatre was a community theatre in Murrysville, Pennsylvania. It operated from 1950 through 1994.
  - Stanley Theatre, 1926-1927; 21 photographs
    The Stanley Theatre was located on Penn avenue at Seventh avenue in downtown Pittsburgh. The theatre was renovated and renamed the Benedum Center of the Performing Arts in 1987. There are a series of seven photographs documenting the construction of the Stanley from early November 1926 through the end of April 1927. Appearing on five of the seven photos is the following - "Theatre and Clark office building for Stanley - Rowland - Clark Corp. Hoffman Henon Co. architects & contractors." These photos appear to have been printed in the 1970s or 1980s. Each photo roughly measures 40' x 24' and there are three copies of each photograph.
    These photographs are filed separately from the rest of the Curtis photographs due to their size.
  - Syria Mosque, 1 photograph
    The Syria Mosque was located on Bigelow Boulevard in Oakland. The building was unveiled in 1919 and demolished in 1991.
  - Third Street Theatre, 1 photograph
    The Third Street Theatre was located on Third Avenue. This was Pittsburgh's first theatre and was in operation from 1817-1820. This is a photograph of an artist's rendering of that theatre.
- People and Miscellaneous, 1914-2007; III.; 55 photographs
  This series is primarily for photos of the entire company of a local Pittsburgh theatre group or similar types of photographs. There are also a few photographs documenting early theatre advertising. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Absolute Pitts, 2002; 2 photographs
    Absolute Pitts was a Pittsburgh comedy troupe. Appearing in these photos are troupe members Hugh McGough, Rosa Copeland Miller, Kathleen Davies, Elinor Nathanson, and Joe Kennedy. Photos by Harvey Nathanson.
  - Amish Monkeys, 2 photographs
    This folder contains two images of the Comedy Improv troupe, the Amish Monkeys.
  - Fine Line Theatre Company, 1978; 1 photograph
    This photograph shows several members of the Fine Line Theatre Company from the 1978/1979 season. Appearing in the photo are Bonnie Gilmore, Robert Koch, Rick Dolnack, Fred Donatelli, and John Waterson.
  - Gargaro's Good Vibrations, 1996; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Gargaro's Good Vibrations 1996 group.
  - Gargaro's Good Vibrations, 1997; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Gargaro's Good Vibrations 1997 group.
  - Gargaro's Stars of Tomorrow, 1997; 1 photograph
    Photograph is of Gargaro's Stars of Tomorrow 1997 group.
  - Hartman, Herman, September 1975
    Herman Hartman was the manager of the Herman Hartman Dinner Theatre and the Mellwood Playhouse.
  - Irene Kaufmann Settlement, 1937-1938; 2 photographs
    Photographs are of the Irene Kaufmann Settlement Players. The 1937 image is the cast of Nine Pine Street, dated October 27, 1937. The 1938 image is the cast of Night of January 16th, dated February 16-17, 1938.
  - Kaspar Monahan exhibit, 7 photographs
    These photographs document a library exhibit on the career of journalist Kaspar Monahan.
  - Little Grovers Theatre Company, 1998; 2 photographs
    Appearing in two photographs are Gillian Strain, Trisha Stahl and Katie McCreary. The three actresses were a part of the Little Grovers Theatre Company. The performances were held on Indiana University of Pennsylvania's campus and included cast and staff members from Indiana University of Pennsylvania's theatre department.
  - Minstrel Broadsides, 1933; 3 photographs
    Photographs are advertisements for performances at various theatres in Pittsburgh. Some theatres included are the Gayety, Pitt, Fulton, Variety, and Academy. The majority of the advertisements are for minstrel and vaudeville shows.
  - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre, 1 slides
    This file contains one unidentified slide from the 1993-1994 season from the Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre. The photograph was taken by David Farmerie.
  - Pittsburg Bulletin, 1 photograph
    Photograph is of the cover of the September 15th, 1900 issue of Pittsburg Bulletin. The cover shows images of the Harry Williams's Academy, Grand Opera House, Duquesne, Bijou, and Alvin theatres.
  - Pittsburgh International Children's Theater, 1998; 2 photographs
    This file contains two photographs which depict graphics that were used in advertising the Pittsburgh International Children's Theater's 1998-1999 Family Series. Images are included for The Three Little Pigs, Al Simmons in Celery Stalks at Midnight, Laura Ingalls Wilder: Growing Up on the Prairie, Landis & Co. Theatre of Magic's Beauty and the Beast, and Circo Zoppe' Europa.
  - Pittsburgh New Works Festival, 2007; 23 photographs (on CD-R disc)
    This file contains a CD-R disc with 23 images from the 17th annual Pittsburgh New Works Festival. The Festival was August 19th through September 30th, 2007.
  - Pittsburgh Screen Club Ball, February 1916; 1 slides
    This glass lantern slide advertises the first annual Pittsburgh Screen Club ball. The reception and dance was held at the Motor Square Garden on February 14th, 1916. Images of Belle Gold, Etta Pillard, Mazie Fogarty, Marion Ballou, and Harry Stubbs appear on the slide and were advertised to appear at the event which benefited the Actor's Fund of America.
  - Robert Morris Colonial Theater, 1977; 1 photograph
    This file contains a publicity photo for the Robert Morris Colonial Theater's 10th anniversary season. Appearing in the photo with a cake are Alan Peter Byrne, Victoria Falco, Thomas V. Gaydos, Leslie L. Birtig, and Jim Sharp.
  - Silver Fox Playhouse
    Photograph includes Pat Kording, Herb Schacter, Ron Grusofsky, and Jeannie Coffy.
  - Theatre Broadsides, 1914-1926; 2 photographs
    Photographs are advertisements for performances at various theatres in Pittsburgh. One photograph is from October 1914, advertising shows such as: Moulin Rouge Girls, Gay Morning Glories, and The Round Up. The second photograph is from September 1926, advertising shows such as: Ben Hur, Wine Woman and Song, and Kandy Kid. Some theatres included are the Gayety, Pitt, Fulton, Variety, and Academy. Photographs are from the Pittsburgh City Photographer's Collection.